CURRICULUM VITAE

VINEET KUMAR

S/O- Shiv Shankar Prasad

Vill- Bhelwa, Ward No- 08

P.O. + P.S.- Chauradano

Dist- East Champaran (Motihari)

State-Bihar

Pin-845302

Contact: -

Mob: 9546582836, 7004719355

E-mail: vineet1mcool@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Seeking position of a Power Utility Engineer where my professional experience and skills will contribute towards achieving goals and objectives of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE: 11 Years Experience in Power Distribution Sector, Smart Metering Field.

PRESENT WORK EXPERIENCE:

Name of the Organization: Saryu Smart Metering Private Limited (Polaris Group)

AMISP for Smart Prepaid Metering, RDSS Scheme MVVNL

Position : Assistant Project Manager

Work Duration : May 2024 to Till Date. (06 Months)

JOB PROFILE AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- > Survey of concerned sub-stations. Survey of concerned feeders. Monitor and survey of DTRs.
- ➤ Achieving Target for Consumer Indexing.
- ➤ Check for proper technicians training if required and arranged accordingly.
- > Check for technician requirements does the agency fulfil or not at the site.
- ➤ Monitor the adequate manpower of the Agency if required report to the concerned.
- Monitor the proper tools, safety related equipment does the Agency have.
- > Security for material safety at Agency stores as well as at site if not report to the concerned.
- ➤ Monitor the flow of materials from store to the Agency and to the site of work if required report to the concerned.
- > Plan and execute with concern Sub-division officials for the substations.
- > If any hindrance or incident happened at the site immediately report to the concerned.
- ➤ Proper coordination with the sub-station in charge and line-staff of the concerned feeder.
- Taking the shutdown of feeders as per plan of work.
- > Cross check for the agency people involved in illegal practices.
- ➤ Help the Agency to submit the old meters to the concerned sub-division.
- ➤ Maintaining Progress of Cirlce.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE:

Name of the Organization: Vindhya Telelinks Limited (VTL) M.P.Birla Group

Revamped Distribution Sector Scheme (RDSS) Project Bihar

Position : Senior Engineer (Projects)

Work Duration : June 2023 to April 2024. (11 Months)

JOB PROFILE AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ➤ Surveying Reconductoring LT line villages, Habitation, HVDS, Feeder separation, segregation, AG line, and preparing Drawing and uploading Bill of Quantity (BOQ).
- ➤ Allocating Manpower to complete specified work in time.
- ➤ Preparing of Material Requisition Note (MRN) from PMS for issuing materials.
- > Contractor billing as per norms of company.
- ➤ Reconciliation of materials issued to contractors.
- ➤ Maintaining Progress of Division and Zone.
- ➤ Planning of New feeders for Network Development/Augmentation.
- ➤ Electrification of LT Line using AB Cable.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE:

Name of the Organization: EDF International Networks

(AMI- Prepaid Smart Metering Project Bihar)

Position : Senior Engineer Deployment (Cluster Lead)
Work Duration : July 2020 to May 2023. (02 Years, 11 Months)

JOB PROFILE AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ➤ Daily Planning with City in charge & Vendor for Productivity.
- ➤ Managing Vendor Team for Site Survey, Meter Installation, WFM Portal Verification.
- ➤ Preparing MIS Report and Meeting with Client (EESL & NBPDCL Officers) regarding project progress, Consumer Billing, Consumer Indexing, Meter Installation.
- ➤ Daily Planning with O&M Technician for Smooth Operation & RC.
- Achieving Target for Meter Installation & New Meter Installation.
- > Achieving Target for Consumer Indexing.
- ➤ Monitoring SLA Non & Never Communication Cases on daily basis.
- As per SLA Manage Vendor to maintain & resolve complaint against faulty Meter, SSI, SSR, RC/DC Cases, Terminal Sparking cases in given 03 hour timeline.
- ➤ Monitoring Safety & Quality related issue at site.
- ➤ Monitoring Manpower Deployment by Vendor at site.
- ➤ Weekly Reconciliation of Old Meter & New Meter at site.
- > Relationship with Client.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Name of the Organization: Nagarjuna Construction Company Limited. (NCC LIMITED)

(Deen Dayal Upadhyaya Gram Jyoti Yojna- Project) AT **JBVNL** (Jharkhand Bijli Vitaran Nigam Limited, Dumka Jharkhand)

Position : Junior Engineer (Electrical)

Work Duration : May 2017 to May 2019. (02 Years)

JOB PROFILE & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- > Surveying partially electrified and un-electrified villages, preparing drawing and uploading Bill of Quantity (BOQ).
- ➤ Allocating Manpower to complete specified work in time.
- ➤ Preparing of Material Requisition Note (MRN) for issuing materials.
- > Contractor billing as per norms of company.
- > Reconciliation of materials issued to contractors.
- ➤ Maintaining Progress of Block and Zone.
- ➤ Planning of New feeders for Network Development/Augmentation.
- > Electrification of LT Line using AB Cable.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Name of the Organization: Essel Vidyut Vitaran Muzaffarpur Limited (ESSEL GROUP).

(Power Distribution Franchise of NBPDCL)

Position: Field Engineer (As a Junior Engineer of SKMCH Subdivision)

Work Duration : March 2014 to March 2017. (03 Years)

JOB PROFILE : (Operation & Maintenance)

JOB PROFILE & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Carry out the Operation & Maintenance of 33/11 KV PSS, 11/0.4 KV DSS, Power Distribution Transformers, 11 KV & 33 KV feeders as per the plan.
- ➤ O& M of 33KV, 11 KV /440 Networks.
- ➤ Operation & maintenance of sub-stations Transformers etc.
- > Attend Breakdowns and Preventive Maintenance.
- > Survey for New Connection, Meter Installation, New Poles, Feeder etc.
- ➤ Reduced in AT & C Losses.
- ➤ Minimize No of Tripping for given uninterrupted power supply to the consumers.
- > Preparation & maintain daily wise of MIS reports.
- ➤ Load Balancing Of DTR.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Name of the Organization : Sam's HR Services Pvt. Ltd.

(Essel Vidyut Vitran Muzaffarpur Limited, Muzaffarpur)

Position : Engineer (As a site Engineer)

Work Duration : July 2012 to March 2014. (01 Year 08 Months)

JOB PROFILE:

- > Survey for New Connection, Meter Installation, New Poles, Feeder etc.
- ➤ Attend Breakdowns and Preventive Maintenance.
- > Preparing the daily target of completing the feeder lengths.
- > Capturing the daily material requirements and generate the need from the store.
- > Prepare daily target MIS.
- ➤ Preparing electrical Network SLD & measurement data of the feeders with the verification of respective utility officers.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:

B.Tech in **Electrical Engineering (EEE**) with 1st Division 67.33% from Punjab Technical University, Jalandhar. (2008-2012)

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

I.Sc (Math) (10+2) with 2nd Division 57.33% from S.N.S College Motihari, Bihar School_Examination Board, Patna (2005-2007)

Matric (10th) with 1st Division 64.33% from High School Chauradano, Bihar School Examination Board, Patna. (2005)

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING:-

TWO Month Industrial Training in Barauni Thermal Power Station (BTPS Barauni)

KEY SKILL: Electrical Site Engineer, O&M and Project work, IPDS & DDUGJY Project. Power distribution Network, Prepaid Smart Metering Project.

SOFTWARE SKILL: BASIC MS OFFICE, MS EXCEL.

PASSPORT NO.- N8848587 DATE OF ISSUE- 17/03/2016

PERSONAL PARTICULARS:

NAME : Vineet Kumar
DATE OF BIRTH : 05/12/1990
MARITAL STATUS : Married
NATIONALITY : Indian

PERMANENT ADDRESS : Vill- Bhelwa, Ward No. - 08

P.O.+P.S.- Chauradano.

Distt- East Champaran, 845302

(Bihar)

FAMILY DETAILS:-

FATHERS NAME : Shiv Shankar Prasad

MOTHERS NAME : Rambha Devi WIFES NAME : Karuna Kumari

ELDER BROTHERS NAME : Gautam Kumar (JEE, Narkatiaganj)

(Govt. Of Bihar, NBPDCL)

YOUNGER BROTHERS NAME: Vikash Kumar

(Indian Railway, ALP, Lucknow)

DECLERATION

I do hereby declare that the above information stated by me is true & correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date:	VINEET KUMAR
Date:	VINEET KUMA

Place: